The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Who's going to lecture?
谁去演讲？
Wow.
哇。
Nice.
真好
Does lecture make sense?
演讲有意义吗？
One, two, three-- sort of.
一二三
OK.
好。
Then I'm going to have an easy job.
然后，我将有一份轻松的工作。
So any pointed questions?
那么有什么尖锐的问题吗？
Any specific pinpoints?
有什么具体的观点吗？
We talked about DFS, but DFS and BFS are sort of related,
我们讨论了DFS，但是DFS和BFS有点相关，
so I'm happy to take both.
所以我很高兴两者兼得。
AUDIENCE: The classification of edges?
听众：边缘的分类？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
We're going to talk about that for sure.
我们将肯定地谈论它。
Anything else?
还要别的吗？
AUDIENCE: I thought it was funny that in undirected graphs,
听众：我觉得很有趣，在无向图中
you could have a backward-- or something like that.
您可能会有倒退-或类似的东西。
PROFESSOR: You don't have to give a radiance.
教授：您不必发光。
I will derive it.
我将得出它。
OK So what edges do we have in directed versus undirected.
好了，那么我们在定向与非定向方面有哪些优势。
OK.
好。
What else?
还有什么？
Cool.
凉。
So I'm going to go through the concepts in DFS really quickly.
因此，我将非常快速地了解DFS中的概念。
And we're going to focus on this.
我们将专注于此。
Because it seems like this is where the issues are.
因为看起来这就是问题所在。
I want this.
我要这个。
So what's a graph?
那是什么图？
AUDIENCE: Interconnected notes.
听众：相互关联的音符。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Fancy names.
花式名字。
Come on.
来吧。
We had this in the last workshop.
我们在上一个讲习班中有这个。
AUDIENCE: A set of edges and vertices.
听众：一组边和顶点。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
How do I draw my vertices?
如何绘制顶点？
AUDIENCE: Dots.
听众：点。
Circles.
界。
PROFESSOR: Dots.
教授：点。
How do I draw my edges?
如何画边缘？
AUDIENCE: Dots.
听众：点。
Lines.
线。
Oops.
哎呀。
PROFESSOR: Looks like a graph?
教授：看起来像图吗？
What kind of graph?
什么样的图？
Directed.
导演。
Because there are arrows and not straight up lines.
因为有箭头而不是直线。
Right?
对？
How do we store graphs in Python?
我们如何在Python中存储图形？
Fancy name first and then implementation.
花式名称，然后执行。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] list.
听众：[听不清]清单。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
What's an adjacency list in Python?
什么是Python中的邻接表？
AUDIENCE: It just shows what notes
听众：它只是显示了哪些注意事项
are adjacent to other notes.
与其他音符相邻。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So what data structure do we use?
那么我们使用什么数据结构？
What elementary python data structure do we use?
我们使用什么基本的python数据结构？
AUDIENCE: A dictionary?
听众：一本字典？
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
So an adjacency list is a dictionary that keys our--
因此，邻接表是一本字典，可用来
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So the keys are the vertices.
因此，关键点是顶点。
So on and so forth.
等等等等。
And what are the values?
值是多少？
AUDIENCE: The nodes?
听众：节点？
Adjacent nodes?
相邻节点？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
A list of something.
清单。
So after our presentation, is the object the one
因此，在我们介绍之后，对象就是一个
that has edges and the simplified
有边缘和简化
one that has vertices.
一个有顶点的
So suppose I want to go for the simple one.
因此，假设我想选择简单的一种。
Where vertices do I have in A's list?
A列表中的哪些顶点？
AUDIENCE: B and G. Right?
听众：B和G。
PROFESSOR: B and G. Sounds good.
教授：B和G。听起来不错。
Right.
对。
What vertices do I have in B's list?
我在B列表中有哪些顶点？
AUDIENCE: C.
听众：C.
PROFESSOR: Why do I not have A?
教授：为什么我没有A？
AUDIENCE: Because it's an arrow, so it can't get to A.
听众：因为是箭头，所以它无法到达A。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So the nodes that I have in the list
所以我在列表中的节点
are the nodes that are reachable from that node.
是从该节点可访问的节点。
I have an edge from B to C, so C is reachable from B.
我从B到C有优势，因此从B可以到达C。
I do not have an edge from B to A
我没有从B到A的优势
because my edges are directed.
因为我的边缘是定向的。
So A is not there.
所以A不在那里。
OK.
好。
Let's write a bit of pseudo- So although it's Python,
让我们写一些伪的东西-尽管是Python，
let's say our graph is represented by a class G. Let's
假设我们的图形由G类表示。
say in this class I have a dictionary called
说这堂课我有一本字典
al, which has what we want.
等，这就是我们想要的。
If I want to get all the vertices in the graph,
如果我想获得图中的所有顶点，
I want to write the method that returns all the vertices.
我想编写返回所有顶点的方法。
What should it look like?
看起来像什么？
Just to make sure that we're all getting the data structure.
只是为了确保我们都得到了数据结构。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So the keys are in the vertices.
因此，关键点在顶点中。
Now, given the vertex, I want its neighbors.
现在，给定顶点，我想要它的邻居。
How do I write that?
我该怎么写？
AUDIENCE: You mean only the vertices that it can go to?
听众：您的意思是仅它可以到达的顶点？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
Dictionary and that vertex.
字典和那个顶点。
PROFESSOR: So return dictionary--
教授：那么请返回字典-
AUDIENCE: al bracket vertex v.
听众：全括号顶点v。
PROFESSOR: Cool.
教授：太好了。
OK.
好。
So this makes sense for everyone, right?
所以这对每个人都有意义，对吧？
Let's start writing DFS because no one
让我们开始编写DFS，因为没有人
said they don't understand DFS.
说他们不了解DFS。
So let's say we have a DFS procedure.
假设我们有一个DFS过程。
And it gets a graph.
它得到一个图。
And it has to do DFS.
并且它必须执行DFS。
What do you need for DFS?
DFS需要什么？
Starting points would be good.
起点会很好。
Just like for DFS, right?
就像DFS一样，对不对？
So how do we do DFS?
那么我们如何做DFS？
AUDIENCE: Start with one node and then we
听众：从一个节点开始，然后我们
keep on following a path down by picking the first vertex.
通过选择第一个顶点继续沿着向下的路径前进。
So like for A, we'd start with A.
因此，像A一样，我们将从A开始。
Then we'd pick the first vertex in its list.
然后，我们在列表中选择第一个顶点。
And then we pick the first vertex in that one's list,
然后我们选择该列表中的第一个顶点，
first vertex in that one's list, until we run out.
该列表中的第一个顶点，直到我们用完为止。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So basically you start today.
所以基本上你今天开始。
And for every neighbor, you recursively
对于每个邻居，您递归地
do DFS on that neighbor.
在该邻居上执行DFS。
Right?
对？
So since this is recursive, let's write it
因此，由于这是递归的，所以让我们编写它
in a recursive manner, nice and easy.
以递归的方式，轻松愉快。
So say DFS calls DFS visit of g and s.
可以说DFS调用g和s进行DFS访问。
And let's say DFS visit takes the graph,
假设使用DFS进行访问，
takes the node that we're visiting,
带我们要访问的节点，
and how are we implementing this?
以及我们如何实施呢？
AUDIENCE: Just return [INAUDIBLE].
听众：只需返回[听不清]。
No.
没有。
It marks as visited.
它标记为已访问。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Marking something as visited is important to lead this.
将某些内容标记为已访问很重要，可以引导它。
So what's the main thing that you do in DFS?
那么，在DFS中主要做什么呢？
Iterate over the neighbors and recurse.
遍历邻居并递归。
Right?
对？
So for n in g neighbors of v called DFS visit of g and n.
因此，对于v中的n个g的n个邻居（称为DFS），访问g和n。
So this is the basic idea.
因此，这是基本思想。
It has some holes that we need to fill because otherwise it
它需要填补一些漏洞，否则
doesn't quite work.
不太有效。
This is going to recurse forever,
这将永远递归，
which is not very good if you have a time
如果有时间，那不是很好
limit that your code needs to obey.
限制您的代码需要遵守。
So how do I make it not recurse forever?
那么如何使它不会永远递归呢？
AUDIENCE: Every time you visit, you're about to visit a node,
听众：每次访问时，您都将访问一个节点，
check if you've already visited it.
检查您是否已经访问过它。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
So we should keep track of the nodes
所以我们应该跟踪节点
that we've already visited and not visit them again.
我们已经访问过并且不再访问它们。
Right.
对。
So you start with A, go to B, go to C,
因此，您从A开始，转到B，转到C，
you'd better not go to A again because you've already
您最好不要再去A了，因为您已经
been there.
到过那里。
So let's implement that this way.
因此，让我们以这种方式实现它。
Let's make a new object called DFS result that
让我们创建一个称为DFS结果的新对象
is sort of that drawer that you have
是那种你拥有的抽屉
where you stick everything in where
你把所有东西都粘在哪里
you don't have a good place.
你没有一个好地方。
So everything I do not have a good place
所以我没有一个好地方
to put it, you just stick it in a drawer.
放进去，就把它放在抽屉里。
And then you can close the drawing that be like,
然后您可以关闭类似的图形，
it's clean.
很干净
Everything's clean.
一切都干净。
So let's say DFS result is that drawer.
因此，可以说DFS的结果就是那个抽屉。
Everything that they need from now on,
从现在开始，他们需要的一切，
we're just going to stick in there.
我们只是要坚持在那里。
So I have an object DFS result.
所以我有一个对象DFS结果。
And we're going to figure out what we put in it.
我们将弄清楚放入其中的内容。
But at the beginning of DFS, I'm going to create that.
但是在DFS的开始，我将创建它。
So create the new object.
因此，创建新对象。
And then I'm going to pass it onto to DFS visit.
然后，我将其传递给DFS访问。
So now we have a drawer where we can put everything we want.
所以现在我们有了一个抽屉，我们可以在这里放想要的所有东西。
So let's keep track of the visited information here.
因此，让我们在这里跟踪访问的信息。
How would I keep track of what nodes I visited?
我将如何跟踪我访问过的节点？
AUDIENCE: In a list?
听众：在列表中？
PROFESSOR: In a list.
教授：在列表中。
So if I do a list, it turns out that in DFS,
因此，如果我列出一个列表，事实证明在DFS中，
and VFS, for that matter, you check
和VFS，为此，您检查
if you visited a node pretty often.
如果您经常访问某个节点。
So it would be kind of slow.
因此，这有点慢。
So let's have a dictionary.
因此，我们来字典。
What are we going to put in that dictionary?
我们要把那本字典放什么？
AUDIENCE: The node [INAUDIBLE] and listed [INAUDIBLE].
听众：节点[听不清]，并列出[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So we're going to have a visited dictionary.
因此，我们将有一个访问字典。
And then the keys are going to be nodes.
然后键将成为节点。
And let's say we're only going to put the nodes that we visit
假设我们只放置访问的节点
in it so we don't have to initialize it.
在其中，因此我们不必初始化它。
And the values are going to be true.
这些价值观将是正确的。
Because if the node is in the dictionary,
因为如果节点在字典中，
it means we visited it.
这意味着我们参观了它。
So for all the nodes that are in there,
因此，对于其中的所有节点，
visited is going to be true.
访问将是真实的。
Sorry.
抱歉。
OK.
好。
So where do I fill this in?
那么我应该在哪里填写呢？
Let's use it.
让我们使用它。
AUDIENCE: Four n and g neighbors, set it to true.
听众：四个n和g邻居，将其设置为true。
But before that--
但在此之前
PROFESSOR: So here?
教授：那么在这里？
AUDIENCE: R not.
听众：R不。
Um.
嗯
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So let's say this.
这么说吧。
Let's say these are lines 1, 2, 3.
假设这些是第1、2、3行。
Line 1.5 or 2.5?
1.5或2.5行？
AUDIENCE: So at n 1.5, check if v is in the dictionary.
听众：所以在n 1.5处，检查v是否在字典中。
PROFESSOR: Here?
教授：这吗？
OK.
好。
If v in r dot visited, then--
如果访问了v in r点，则-
AUDIENCE: Return.
听众：回来。
Then 2.5, set r dot n to true.
然后2.5，将r dot n设置为true。
You would only do it n times--
你只会做n次
PROFESSOR: Wait.
教授：等等。
So here you're saying say r dot visited of n equals true?
因此，您在这里说的是n的r点访问是否等于true？
AUDIENCE: Oh, no.
听众：哦，不。
Change the v in v visited return,
更改已访问退货中的v，
change that into a loop.
改变成一个循环。
Put that after the loop.
将其放在循环之后。
Put that into the loop.
将其放入循环中。
And it's n visited to the [INAUDIBLE].
而且它已经访问过[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: n in r dot visited-- we probably want not n, right?
教授：n点中有n个访问过-我们可能不想要n个，对吧？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
R dot visited is true and then the DFS.
访问的R点为true，然后为DFS。
So will this achieve the thing that I wanted at the beginning.
因此这将实现我一开始想要的东西。
You start at A, you go to B, you go to C,
您从A开始，进入B，进入C，
and then you do not go to A?
然后你不去A？
Not quite.
不完全的。
AUDIENCE: We haven't had our starting yet.
听众：我们还没有开始。
Yeah.
是的
We could add V at the beginning and check at the end.
我们可以在开头添加V，然后在末尾检查。
Because that's only the visited, right?
因为那只是参观者，对不对？
PROFESSOR: So I think I like Christian's suggestion.
教授：所以我认为我喜欢克里斯蒂安的建议。
r dot visited of v is true.
v的r点访问为true。
And then we can remove it from here.
然后我们可以从这里删除它。
AUDIENCE: It has to be [INAUDIBLE]
听众：必须是[听不清]
because the other case is going to cover
因为另一种情况将涵盖
for if you visited again.
如果您再次访问。
But the first time it's being called, it's not checking--
但是第一次调用它时，它并没有检查-
PROFESSOR: Well you mean the first time here?
教授：那您是第一次来吗？
AUDIENCE: The first call that's being made,
听众：第一次拨打电话，
and the recursive call, it's going
和递归调用
to be as if it's not into the visited node.
好像它不在访问节点中一样。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
But this is at the beginning.
但这只是开始。
Right?
对？
So this calls DFS visit to the starting node.
因此，这将调用DFS访问起始节点。
Do we care?
我们在乎吗？
So I think this should work.
所以我认为这应该可行。
It's not the only way to write it, but it's reasonably clean.
这不是唯一的编写方法，但是它相当干净。
It's easy to reason about, and it works.
这很容易推理，并且有效。
Does it make sense to everyone?
这对所有人有意义吗？
OK.
好。
We're going to change things a little bit.
我们将稍作更改。
So instead of using visited, we're
因此，我们不使用访问，而是
going to keep track for every node of its parent.
跟踪其父节点的每个节点。
So the node that we visited from.
因此，我们访问的节点。
So we're not going to use visited anymore.
因此，我们将不再使用访问。
Instead we're going to use parent of v
相反，我们将使用v的父级
is going to be some other node.
将成为其他节点。
So what I want is for this graph,
所以我想要这张图
I said I'm going to go from A to B, and then from B to C.
我说过我将从A到B，然后从B到C。
So I want the parent of B to be A, and the parent of C to be B.
所以我希望B的父母是A，C的父母是B。
Make sense for everyone?
对每个人都有意义吗？
So what's the parent of A?
那么A的父母是谁？
AUDIENCE: None.
听众：没有。
PROFESSOR: None's a good value, right?
教授：没有一个好的价值吧？
There's no parent.
没有父母
OK.
好。
So how would I modify this code to write that?
那么我将如何修改此代码以编写该代码？
AUDIENCE: Stick a line in 2.75 and establish 3b
观众：在2.75分界线并建立3b
as the parent of n.
作为n的父母。
PROFESSOR: So r dot parent?
教授：那么，父母吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah, of n is v.
听众：是的，n为v。
PROFESSOR: Of n is v. Good.
教授：n是v。
And I don't have visited anymore,
而且我不再去了，
so this line is going to blow up.
所以这条线会炸毁。
So what do I do instead?
那我该怎么办呢？
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
It doesn't have a parent?
它没有父母吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So if it doesn't have a parent, we didn't visit it.
因此，如果没有父母，我们就没有拜访它。
So the parents works just like visited,
父母的工作就像拜访一样
except the values are not going to be all true.
除了这些值不会全部为真。
They're going to be something a bit more useful.
它们将变得更有用。
AUDIENCE: We can't test for none because the first one has
观众：我们无法测试，因为第一个有
a value of none.
无值。
PROFESSOR: But they're not testing for none,
教授：但是他们并没有全力以赴，
we're saying is it in the dictionary or not?
我们是说在字典里还是没有？
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
OK.
好。
PROFESSOR: That's a good point.
教授：很好。
You could be testing for none.
您可能没有测试。
That wouldn't work.
那是行不通的。
So you have to write the check like this.
因此，您必须像这样写支票。
And we're going to erase this because otherwise, it's
我们将删除它，因为否则
going to throw an exception.
将引发异常。
And what else do we need?
我们还需要什么？
There's one missing parent.
有一个失踪的父母。
AUDIENCE: Inverse form?
听众：逆形式？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Where do I say that?
我在哪说
AUDIENCE: In DFS.
听众：在DFS中。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
One, two, three, which line?
一二三
1.5, 2.5, 3.5?
1.5、2.5、3.5？
AUDIENCE: 2.5.
观众：2.5。
PROFESSOR: 2.5.
教授：2.5。
All right, so here.
好的，这里。
What do I write?
我写什么？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: Parent of s is none.
听众：的父不是。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So r dot parent s is none.
所以点双亲是无。
So now this works.
所以现在这可行。
Right?
对？
Any questions so far?
到目前为止有什么问题吗？
Nope.
不。
Basic DFS works.
基本的DFS可以工作。
Everyone's happy with it?
每个人都满意吗？
Let's try to track it for this graph here.
让我们尝试在此处跟踪此图。
And you're going to be in a better position than me
而且你会比我处于更好的位置
because I'm not sure I can see the graph all
因为我不确定是否可以看到所有图表
the way from here.
从这里走的路。
Almost.
几乎。
So let's have the parents or the parent's dictionary here.
因此，让我们这里有父母或父母的字典。
And here, let's write the call structure as it will happen.
在这里，让我们编写将要发生的调用结构。
So where do I start?
那我从哪里开始呢？
DFS of A, right?
D的DFS，对不对？
DFS of A. And this is going to call DFS visit A.
DFS的A。这将称为DFS访问A。
What are A's neighbors?
A的邻居是什么？
AUDIENCE: b and g.
听众：b和g。
PROFESSOR: Cool.
教授：太好了。
Is b in parents?
父母有b吗？
What's in parents, at this point?
父母现在在做什么？
AUDIENCE: Just a.
听众：只是。
Oh.
哦。
PROFESSOR: A is none.
教授：A不是。
Good.
好。
Excellent.
优秀的。
So B is not in parents, so what am I going to do?
所以B不在父母中，那我该怎么办？
And it's the parents in visited.
这是拜访的父母。
Right?
对？
What's B's parents?
B的父母是谁？
AUDIENCE: A.
听众：A.
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
I'm going to call DFS visit of B. These children.
我将打电话给B的DFS访问。这些孩子。
C. Is C parents?
C.是C父母吗？
No?
没有？
What happens?
怎么了？
Feel free to take over.
随时接管。
When you get it, feel free to start talking,
掌握之后，请随时开始讲话，
and I can just write.
我可以写
AUDIENCE: Of C.
听众：来自C。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
What else?
还有什么？
PROFESSOR: C's parent is B. So I'm
教授：C的父母是B。所以我
in B. The only child is C. C is not in parents.
在B中。唯一的孩子是C。C不在父母中。
C gets in parent.
C成为父母。
C's parent is B. Call DFS visit of C, what are C's children?
C的父母是B。打电话给C的DFS访问，C的孩子是什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] and d.
听众：[听不清]和d。
PROFESSOR: So we're wondering about the order, right?
教授：所以我们想知道订单，对吗？
Let's assume that in the adjacency list,
假设在邻接列表中，
all the nodes are in alphabetical order.
所有节点均按字母顺序排列。
So I'm going to have A, D, and F. OK.
所以我要有A，D和F。好的。
Is A in parents?
父母有A吗？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: Is D in parents?
教授：父母有D吗？
AUDIENCE: No.
听众：不。
PROFESSOR: So what happens?
教授：那会发生什么？
AUDIENCE: Parents visit D. D's parent is C.
听众：父母拜访D。D的父母是C。
PROFESSOR: D's neighbors?
教授：D的邻居？
AUDIENCE: E and F.
观众：E和F。
PROFESSOR: E is in the-- no.
教授：E在-不。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Cool.
教授：太好了。
Does E have any children?
E有孩子吗？
AUDIENCE: No.
听众：不。
PROFESSOR: So I'm done.
教授：我完成了。
I get out of it, right?
我摆脱它，对不对？
Is F in parents?
父母有F吗？
AUDIENCE: No.
听众：不。
PROFESSOR: F's parent is?
教授：F的父母是？
Cool.
凉。
F doesn't have any children.
F没有孩子。
Right?
对？
So I get out of this DFS visit.
因此，我离开了这次DFS访问。
I'm done with F. So I get out of this visit.
我已经完成了F。所以我离开了这次访问。
And I get back to this one.
我回到这一点。
I'm done with D, and I'm at F. Is F in parents?
我完成了D，现在在F。F是父母吗？
OK.
好。
So what kind of edge is C to F?
那么C到F的优势是什么？
AUDIENCE: Forward.
听众：转发。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So forward maybe tree.
所以前进也许树。
Let's start with the easy ones.
让我们从简单的开始。
So now we've gone forward with AB, BC, CD, DE, and DF.
因此，现在我们开始使用AB，BC，CD，DE和DF。
What kind of edges are these ones?
这些是什么样的边缘？
Tree edges.
树的边缘。
Does anyone know why they're called tree edges?
有谁知道为什么他们被称为树边缘？
So if you look at the parent pointers that they have there,
因此，如果您查看它们在那里的父指针，
they're going to end up defining a tree.
他们最终将定义一棵树。
And the tree is, the tree shows the order
树是，树显示顺序
in which DFS looked at the notes.
DFS在其中查看了注释。
So let me erase this and draw the tree for DFS
因此，让我删除它并为DFS绘制树
that we had so far.
我们到目前为止。
So we started at A, then we went to B. Then we went to C, then
所以我们从A开始，然后去了B。然后我们去了C，然后
we went to D, E, F. So this is all part of the DFS tree.You
我们去了D，E，F。所以这都是DFS树的一部分。
can see that for all these nodes,
可以看到对于所有这些节点，
their parent pointers point the right way.
它们的父指针指向正确的方向。
So if you have parent pointers for every node,
因此，如果每个节点都有父指针，
this is going to give you a tree.
这会给你一棵树。
So these are tree edges because they're part of this tree.
这些是树的边缘，因为它们是该树的一部分。
So now we have this edge from C to F.
所以现在我们有了从C到F的优势。
And this is what kind of edge?
这是什么样的优势？
Forward edge.
前缘。
Why is it a forward edge?
为什么是前缘？
AUDIENCE: Somewhere up higher in the tree
听众：在树上更高的某个地方
is trying to get somewhere lower on the tree.
试图降到树下的某个地方。
It's going forward in time.
这是及时的。
PROFESSOR: So it's going from a node in the tree
教授：所以它是从树中的一个节点开始的
to a node's child in the tree.
到树中节点的孩子。
Sorry, not child.
对不起，不是孩子。
Descendant.
后裔。
So F is strictly under C. So yeah.
所以F严格在C之下。是的。
It takes us forward in time.
它使我们及时前进。
It's a shortcut in the tree.
这是树上的捷径。
So that's why it's a forward edge.
这就是为什么这是一个前沿。
So we now have two types of edges so far.
因此，到目前为止，我们有两种类型的边缘。
Tree edges and forward edges.
树边缘和前边缘。
AUDIENCE: So tree edges [INAUDIBLE]?
听众：那么树的边缘[听不清]？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So the tree edges are the ones that DFS follows.
因此，树边缘就是DFS遵循的边缘。
All of these are tree edges.
所有这些都是树的边缘。
Yes.
是。
AUDIENCE: So like an edge from B to C,
听众：就像从B到C的优势一样，
why can't that be a forward edge?
为什么不能成为前锋？
Because technically it's not a shortcut, right?
因为从技术上讲这不是捷径，对吗？
But it's saying it's pointing to the children,
但这是指孩子们
but it only has one child.
但只有一个孩子
PROFESSOR: Because that's the edge that DFS took.
教授：因为那是DFS的优势。
So the edges that we actually follow in DFS
所以我们在DFS中实际遵循的优势
have a special name, and they're tree edges.
有一个特殊的名字，它们是树的边缘。
So first off, the most important edges
首先，最重要的优势
are the edges that make up your DFS tree.
是构成DFS树的边缘。
And that's why those are tree edges.
这就是为什么这些是树的边缘。
We don't even look at the other types.
我们甚至不看其他类型。
If you have an edge and DFS followed it, it's a tree edge.
如果您有一条边缘并且DFS紧随其后，则它是树边缘。
Done.
做完了
So these are all tree edges.
这些都是树的边缘。
We don't care about the other definitions.
我们不在乎其他定义。
So don't be ashamed to ask questions about this
所以不要以问这个问题为耻
because this is hard to understand.
因为这很难理解。
It's an issue we're trying to clarify here.
这是我们要在此处澄清的问题。
So the point, why we're doing that example,
关键是为什么我们要做这个例子，
is to figure this out.
是要弄清楚这一点。
So please do ask your questions.
所以请问您的问题。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: So is it edges that are followed at any point
听众：在任何时候都遵循的边缘
during the search process?
在搜索过程中？
I guess they're edges that never get touched.
我想它们是永不动摇的边缘。
Right?
对？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So when I'm at C, and I look at this edge,
因此，当我在C语言时，我会看着这个优势，
F is already in parents.
F已经在父母中了。
So this edge is not going to be followed by DFS.
因此，DFS将不会跟随这一优势。
There are some other types of edges
还有一些其他类型的边缘
that will not be followed.
那将不会被遵循。
And we'll get to that by the time DFS completes.
在DFS完成时，我们将解决这个问题。
Yes.
是。
AUDIENCE: You mean that like G to C is not--
听众：您的意思是说，从G到C并非-
PROFESSOR: You're ruining my example, man.
教授：老兄，你毁了我的榜样。
I'm supposed to ask you that later on.
我应该稍后再问你。
So let's let go through it and see what kind of edge it is.
因此，让我们看一下它是什么样的优势。
You're right, but let's pretend we don't know that.
您是对的，但是我们假装不知道这一点。
And we'll see as we follow the DFS.
然后我们将按照DFS进行查看。
OK.
好。
So yep.
是的
That one's a forward edge.
那是一个前沿。
We'll deal with it later.
我们稍后再处理。
We're here.
我们在这里
We decided that C to F is a forward edge.
我们认为C到F是一个前沿。
F is already in parents.
F已经在父母中了。
So we're going to return from DFS visit
因此，我们将从DFS访问中返回
C. We're in DFS visit V. We're done with C.
C.我们在DFS中访问V。C已经完成。
Do we have anything else to do here?
我们在这里还有其他事情吗？
So we go up to A. We're done with B. And we look at G. A
因此，我们转到A。B完成了。我们来看G。
to G. Is G in parents?
给G。父母中有G吗？
No.
没有。
So we're going to call it.
因此，我们将其称为。
So A, B. DFS visit G. What are G's neighbors?
因此，A，B。DFS访问G。G的邻居是什么？
AUDIENCE: C.
听众：C.
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So is C in parents?
父母的C也一样吗？
Actually I was wrong.
其实我错了。
Sorry.
抱歉。
So C is in parents, so we're not going to visit it.
因为C在父母中，所以我们不会去拜访它。
So let's see how the tree looks like at this point.
现在，让我们看看树的外观。
So it looks like this.
所以看起来像这样。
Is C a child of G?
C是G的孩子吗？
So I'm wondering about this edge that we chose not to follow.
所以我想知道我们选择不遵循的这一优势。
We followed A to G so we know this is actually the edge.
我们遵循A到G的原则，因此我们知道这实际上是优势。
So from this edge, G to C, I'm wondering what kind of edge
所以从G到C的这个边缘，我想知道什么样的边缘
it is.
它是。
So C is not G's child, right?
所以C不是G的孩子，对吗？
So another forward edge.
因此，另一个前沿。
Sorry.
抱歉。
I got confused earlier because they
我之前很困惑，因为他们
look the same in a drawing.
在图纸上看起来一样。
So it's not a forward edge, then it's a cross edge.
因此，它不是前边缘，而是交叉边缘。
There's one more edge that we haven't
还有一个我们没有的优势
talked about because it was too early in the search.
谈论是因为搜索尚为时过早。
And that edge is from C to A. So if you remember
那边是从C到A。所以如果你还记得
there, we were in DFS visit C. And the first thing we did
在那里，我们在DFS中访问了C。我们做的第一件事
was we looked at A, we said, hey it's already in parents,
是我们看着A，我们说，嘿，它已经在父母那里了，
so we're not going to visit it.
所以我们不会去参观它。
So DFS did not follow the edge C to A.
因此，DFS没有跟随C到A的边缘。
That edge looks like this.
那个边缘看起来像这样。
What kind of edge is it?
这是什么优势？
Back edge.
后边缘。
AUDIENCE: Wait.
听众：等等。
So it has to be direct descendant in order
因此它必须是顺序的直接后代
to be a forward edge?
成为前锋？
Because they are related through A, right?
因为它们通过A相关，对吗？
C and G?
C和G？
PROFESSOR: So you have to look and which direction does it go?
教授：那你必须看一下，往哪个方向走？
Does it go down the tree or up the tree?
它是沿着树走还是向上走？
AUDIENCE: It's going down if you consider G to C. From G to C,
听众：如果您考虑G到C，它会下降。从G到C，
so it's a cross edge.
所以这是一个交叉的边缘。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
But is C G's descendant?
但是C G是后代吗？
AUDIENCE: No.
听众：不。
But they are related.
但是它们是相关的。
PROFESSOR: They're related, but they're just
教授：它们是相关的，但它们只是
related because they're in the tree.
相关，因为它们在树上。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
So it's only directly descendants?
所以这只是直接的后代吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So DFS puts together a tree.
因此DFS整理了一棵树。
A forward edge is a shortcut in that tree.
前缘是该树中的快捷方式。
It lets you go forward in the VFS.
它使您可以在VFS中前进。
A backward edge points to a parent in the tree,
后缘指向树中的父级，
so it lets you go back in time.
这样您就可以回到过去。
A cross edge takes you from one point to another point.
十字边缘将您从一个点带到另一个点。
And it's not a forward edge, not a backward edge.
它不是前缘，也不是后缘。
So it takes you in a whole different world.
因此，它带您进入了一个全新的世界。
So C, A, G, has-- A, G is the sub-tree,
因此C，A，G具有-A，G是子树，
and then this guy's this other sub-tree,
然后这个家伙是另一个子树，
and they're different little worlds.
他们是不同的小世界。
And this edge goes from one to the other.
这个优势从一个延伸到另一个。
So the algorithm to decide what kind of an edge it is, let's
因此，决定该边缘类型的算法，让我们
put it together.
把它放在一起。
Which edge do we look at, which type do we think about first?
我们要看哪个边缘，首先要考虑哪种类型？
Tree edge.
树边缘。
So DFS followed the edge.
因此DFS紧随其后。
It's a tree edge.
这是树的边缘。
So we have tree edges.
所以我们有树的边缘。
What do we do next?
接下来我们要做什么？
So say we have an edge from u to v. If DFS follows it,
假设我们从u到v都有优势。如果DFS跟随它，
it's a tree edge.
这是树的边缘。
If not, then what question do I ask myself?
如果没有，那么我会问自己什么问题？
AUDIENCE: It could be one of three edges then,
听众：那可能是三个优势之一
back, forward, or cross.
向后，向前或交叉。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So let's try to write a simple algorithm
因此，让我们尝试编写一个简单的算法
so that if I ask you this on a quiz,
因此，如果我在测验中问您这个问题，
you can decide which is which.
您可以决定哪个。
AUDIENCE: So I think that you look forward
听众：所以我认为你很期待
if u is the parent of v.
如果您是v的父母。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So if u is a parent of v-- well, let's say ascendant.
因此，如果u是v的父级，那么，假设上升。
It's not just the direct parent, but this
不只是直系亲属
is the right intuition.
是正确的直觉。
Then what kind of edge is it?
那是什么样的优势呢？
AUDIENCE: Then it's the forward edge.
听众：那就是前沿。
PROFESSOR: So the edge is from u to v. If u is a parent of v,
教授：所以边是从u到v。如果u是v的父级，
forward edge.
前缘。
Good.
好。
Otherwise?
除此以外？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Then?
然后？
AUDIENCE: Then backward edge.
听众：然后落后。
Else cross edge.
其他边缘。
PROFESSOR: Does this make sense?
教授：这有意义吗？
So these are the four types of edges.
因此，这是四种类型的边。
DFS takes the edge, it's a forward edge.
DFS占据了优势，这是一个前沿。
If not, we draw the DFS tree.
如果没有，我们绘制DFS树。
And we see does the edge go forward
我们看到优势在前进
in the tree, forward edge.
在树上，向前边缘。
Does it go backward, backward edge.
它向后走，向后走。
Does it grow between completely unrelated nodes, cross edge.
它是否在完全不相关的节点之间交叉边缘增长。
OK.
好。
Now let me ask another question.
现在让我问另一个问题。
Let's suppose we do this DFS thing again,
假设我们再次执行此DFS操作，
but let's suppose we do it on an undirected graph.
但是，假设我们在无向图上执行此操作。
What types of edges do I have?
我有哪些类型的边缘？
Anyone remember off the top of their heads?
有人还记得吗？
Don't think so, right?
不这样认为，对吧？
So let's do it and find out.
因此，让我们去做并找出答案。
So let me see where do I get some room.
所以，让我看看我在哪里可以得到一些空间。
Here.
这里。
Let's write the tree that's we're going to go.
让我们写一棵我们要去的树。
So let's do a VFS of this quickly and write the tree.
因此，让我们快速进行此VFS并编写树。
So we start at A, then what?
那么我们从A开始，那又如何呢？
Then?
然后？
D. E.
德
AUDIENCE: And go back to D. It could go from C to A.
听众：然后回到D。它可以从C到A。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So we have C to A. What kind of edge is this?
所以我们有C到A。这是什么优势？
AUDIENCE: Backward edge.
听众：向后边缘。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So we still have tree edges for sure and backward edges.
因此，我们仍然具有确定的树边缘和向后的边缘。
AUDIENCE: How do you get from C to A?
听众：您如何从C到A？
PROFESSOR: This was supposed to happen way before.
教授：这应该是以前发生的。
So we went A, B, C, and then when we were at C, oh.
所以我们去了A，B，C，然后当我们在C时，哦。
Sorry.
抱歉。
My bad.
我的错。
So we went from A to B, B to C, and then A
所以我们从A到B，从B到C，再到A
was the first thing in C's adjacency list.
是C的邻接表中的第一件事。
So we saw this back edge.
因此，我们看到了此后边缘。
So C to D, D to E, D to F.
所以C到D，D到E，D到F。
AUDIENCE: E to F?
听众：从E到F？
Or F to C?
还是F到C？
PROFESSOR: And then F to C. So what kind of edge is this?
教授：然后是F到C。那么这是什么优势？
AUDIENCE: Backward.
听众：向后。
PROFESSOR: So none of these guys.
教授：所以这些家伙都不是。
And then we're all the way back at A, right?
然后我们一直回到A，对不对？
A to-- oh.
哦〜
Sorry.
抱歉。
No we're not done.
不，我们还没有完成。
So C to D, D to E, D to F, then we're back at C. And C to G.
所以从C到D，从D到E，从D到F，然后我们回到C。从C到G。
AUDIENCE: There's supposed to be a line between C and F?
听众：应该在C和F之间有一条界线吗？
PROFESSOR: Oh, yeah.
教授：哦，是的。
Sorry.
抱歉。
I guess I can't copy.
我想我不能复制。
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine.
一，二，三，四，五，六，七，八，九。
Now it's right.
现在是对的。
Thank you.
谢谢。
OK.
好。
So what am I missing?
那我想念什么呢？
Edge from C to G. What kind of edge?
从C到G的边缘。什么样的边缘？
AUDIENCE: C and G?
听众：C和G？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So we have tree edges and we have backward edges.
所以我们有树边，我们有后边。
What do we not have?
我们没有什么？
Forward edges and cross edges, right?
前边缘和交叉边缘，对吗？
AUDIENCE: You need one from A to G. A and G are related.
听众：您需要从A到G中的一个。A和G是相关的。
PROFESSOR: What edge is this?
教授：这是什么优势？
Cool.
凉。
Thanks.
谢谢。
AUDIENCE: You never add those, though, right?
听众：不过，您永远不会添加这些内容，对吗？
You just see that A was in the parent's list, and be like, OK.
您只要看到A在父母的列表中，就可以了。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So for all the edges that are not tree edges,
因此，对于不是树边缘的所有边缘，
DFS doesn't actually follow them.
DFS实际上并没有遵循它们。
We just care about them because other algorithms
我们只关心它们，因为其他算法
care about them.
关心他们。
They let you compute fancy things on the graph.
他们让您计算图表上的奇特事物。
OK.
好。
So are we good with the types?
那么我们对类型好吗？
So why can't I have a forward edge?
那么，为什么我不能拥有前锋呢？
So there are two types of edges I can't have,
所以我无法提供两种类型的边缘，
cross edges and forward edges.
交叉边缘和前边缘。
Why can't I have a forward edge?
为什么我不能拥有前锋？
On an undirected graph?
在无向图上？
So in order to have a forward edge,
因此，为了拥有前缘，
I would have to go C, D, F. And then not follow this edge.
我必须走C，D，F。然后再不走这条路。
I mean not see this edge here.
我的意思是在这里看不到这个优势。
Right?
对？
If this edge would be undirected,
如果这条边是无方向的，
I would say, hey, it goes from F to C. It's a background edge.
我会说，嘿，它是从F到C。这是背景边缘。
So I would have seen this edge when I would have been in C.
所以当我在C语言中时，我会看到这种优势。
So I'm comparing this tree with this tree,
所以我要比较这棵树和这棵树，
and trying to figure out why they're different.
并试图弄清它们为何与众不同。
How does a forward edge look like?
前缘看起来如何？
You have a node u, then you have some more tree stuff.
您有一个节点u，那么您还有更多树内容。
And from here, you got to v. And then when you're at v,
然后从这里到v。然后在v处
you didn't see the edge.
你没有看到边缘。
Right?
对？
Because if you would have seen it,
因为如果您会看到它，
it would have been a background edge.
这本来是背景边缘。
So you can only see the edge from u to v later on.
因此，您以后只能看到从u到v的边缘。
So this is tree edges, a bunch of tree edges,
这就是树的边缘，一堆树的边缘，
and this is a forward edge.
这是一个前沿。
In an undirected graph, this never
在无向图中，这永远不会
happens because when you're at v,
之所以发生是因为当您在v时，
you're going to see the edge.
您将看到边缘。
And you're going to mark it as a backward edge.
您将把它标记为向后边缘。
So forward edges can ever happen.
因此，可能会发生前缘。
Yes?
是？
No?
没有？
Is everyone happy?
大家开心吗？
So cross edges.
因此交叉边缘。
Why can't they happen?
他们为什么不能发生？
A cross edge can never happen because in order
交叉边缘永远不会发生，因为顺序
for a cross edge to happen, I would have to go A, B, C,
为了实现交叉优势，我必须走A，B，C，
visit C's children, then go up and go somewhere else.
拜访C的孩子，然后上去其他地方。
And then see this edge.
然后看到这个边缘。
But, hey, when I was at C, why didn't I see this edge?
但是，嘿，当我在C时，为什么没有看到这个优势？
Why did I only see it later?
为什么我以后才看到？
If it's an undirected graph, I would see this edge here
如果它是无向图，我会在这里看到此边缘
and it would be a forward edge.
这将是一个前沿。
Sorry.
抱歉。
A tree edge, because that would take it.
树边缘，因为那样会占用它。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: So is it just when you're-- is it just
听众：只是当您在吗？
because it's the way you traverse in DFS or would it
因为这是您在DFS中遍历的方式，还是会
apply generally to VFS as well?
一般也适用于VFS？
PROFESSOR: VFS doesn't have forward and backward.
教授：VFS没有前进和后退。
Yeah.
是的
VFS is completely different.
VFS完全不同。
So these are all DFS terms, purely DFS.
这些都是DFS术语，纯粹是DFS。
OK.
好。
So no forward edges, no cross edges.
因此，没有前边缘，没有交叉边缘。
And if you forget which ones you can and can't have,
而且，如果您忘记了哪些可以拥有和不能拥有，
now you know how to reason about it quickly and remember.
现在您知道了如何快速推理并记住。
Yes?
是？
OK.
好。
So this is DFS.
这就是DFS。
Are we all happy with DFS?
我们都对DFS满意吗？
Let's talk about topological sorting then.
然后让我们讨论拓扑排序。
Because it's really useful.
因为它真的很有用。
It's one of the few algorithms that is really useful
这是真正有用的少数算法之一
and that you might have to write yourself later.
并且您以后可能不得不写自己。
So suppose these are classes.
因此，假设这些是类。
So let's get back to this oriented thing
让我们回到这个导向的东西
and suppose these are classes.
并假设这些是类。
And the edges show prerequisites.
边缘显示了先决条件。
So A is a prerequisite of B. Like say A is 601
因此，A是B的先决条件。比如说A是601
and B is 6006.
B是6006
And you have to take 601 before you take 6006.
而且您必须先取601，然后再取6006。
Otherwise you will cry during programming assignments.
否则，您将在编程作业期间哭泣。
So what we want to do is these are
所以我们要做的是
all the classes you need to graduate.
您需要毕业的所有课程。
We need to come up with an order in which you can take them
我们需要拿出一个可以带他们去的订单
so that when you take a class, you took all the prerequisites.
这样，当您上课时，您就具备了所有先决条件。
So you don't cry while you're taking that class.
因此，上课时您不会哭泣。
How do we do that?
我们该怎么做？
And let's use this graph as an example.
让我们以该图为例。
AUDIENCE: Use a directed graph that's acyclic?
听众：使用非循环有向图？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Is this graph acyclic?
该图是非循环的吗？
AUDIENCE: No.
听众：不。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So what then?
那又如何呢？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So if the graph has a cycle,
教授：因此，如果图形具有循环，
you can't solve the problem.
你无法解决问题。
It has no solution.
它没有解决方案。
AUDIENCE: It's like those cardboard boxes
听众：就像那些纸板箱
that [INAUDIBLE].
那个[听不清]。
It's really annoying.
真烦人。
PROFESSOR: I don't know the cardboard box problem.
教授：我不知道纸板箱有问题。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
You know those cardboard boxes with the four flaps
你知道那些带有四个口盖的纸板箱
when you close them, and they close like-- Yeah.
当您关闭它们时，它们会像-是的那样关闭。
Those are so annoying.
那些真烦人。
That's just what this reminds me of.
这就是让我想起的。
That's all.
就这样。
Continue.
继续。
PROFESSOR: There's a cycle there,
教授：那里有一个循环，
so you can't just put them in an order.
所以你不能只是把它们整理好。
Right?
对？
You have to violate the repeating variance somehow.
您必须以某种方式违反重复的方差。
And you do that by twisting the edges.
然后通过扭曲边缘来做到这一点。
So if we had classes A, B, C, you cannot take them in any
因此，如果我们有A，B，C类，则不能将它们带入任何
order.
订购。
Right?
对？
If you take A first, you would need C. If you take B first,
如果您先选择A，则需要C。如果您先选择B，
you would need A. If you take C first, you would need B.
您将需要A。如果您首先学习C，那么您将需要B。
So you can't start with any of them.
因此，您不能从任何一个开始。
So if you have a cycle in a graph,
因此，如果您在图中有一个循环，
it's not a dependency graph.
它不是依赖图。
You can't compute dependencies.
您无法计算依赖关系。
So topological sorts only works on cyclic graphs.
因此，拓扑排序仅适用于循环图。
So acyclic graph.
所以无环图。
And what else?
还有什么？
So a dependency graph is a special kind of graph.
因此，依赖图是一种特殊的图。
And I'm looking for three fancy words.
我正在寻找三个花哨的单词。
You already have two.
您已经有两个了。
So we have acyclic and we have graph.
所以我们有一个非循环的，我们有一个图。
Directed.
导演。
So you have to have a directed, so
所以你必须有一个指导，所以
that you know which class goes first.
您知道哪个班第一。
Needs to be acyclic, otherwise there's no solution.
需要是非循环的，否则没有解决方案。
Needs to be a graph, because that's
需要是一张图，因为那是
what we're talking about.
我们在说什么。
So the shortening for this is a DAG.
因此，简称DAG。
OK.
好。
How do you compute an order?
您如何计算订单？
So say we remove that edge.
所以说我们去掉那条边缘。
How do we compute an order?
我们如何计算订单？
AUDIENCE: You run DFS and then print out the reverse.
听众：运行DFS，然后打印相反的内容。
PROFESSOR: And then print out the reverse?
教授：然后打印出反面吗？
AUDIENCE: Of your final output.
听众：您的最终输出。
PROFESSOR: Which is?
教授：那是什么？
AUDIENCE: Your final output?
听众：您的最终输出？
You want me to do it on a graph?
你要我在图表上做吗？
PROFESSOR: You can tell me how to change the codes, too.
教授：您也可以告诉我如何更改密码。
So I'm not sure what-- you said print the reverse of something,
所以我不知道是什么-您说的是打印相反的东西，
but what's that thing?
那是什么
AUDIENCE: So I go down a path, right,
听众：所以我走了一条路，对，
until you've hit all the nodes, then
直到您击中所有节点，然后
basically you start from the last node
基本上你从最后一个节点开始
you visited and print out the reverse of that.
您访问过并打印相反的内容。
Go back to the first node.
返回第一个节点。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So you're saying I go A, B, C, D, E, and then
所以你说我去A，B，C，D，E，然后
I print E, D, C, B, A?
我打印E，D，C，B，A吗？
AUDIENCE: No.
听众：不。
Because that wouldn't hit all the nodes.
因为那不会覆盖所有节点。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
He's on the right track, by the way, so that's why we're--
顺便说一句，他走的路正确，所以这就是我们-
AUDIENCE: You go A, B, C, D, E, F,
听众：您去A，B，C，D，E，F，
G, and you print G, F, E, D, C, B, A.
G，然后打印G，F，E，D，C，B，A。
PROFESSOR: OK so we print them in the reverse.
教授：好的，所以我们将它们反向打印。
So you're printing them in the order in which you're
因此，您将按照打印顺序进行打印
done with them after DFS?
DFS之后对他们做了什么？
No.
没有。
You're printing them in the reverse order
您以相反的顺序打印它们
of the order which you visited them?
您去拜访他们的顺序？
So you visited A, B, C, D, E, F, G,
因此，您访问了A，B，C，D，E，F，G，
so you're saying print G, F, E, D, C, B, A.
所以您说的是G，F，E，D，C，B，A
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
Because in lecture wasn't it flipped,
因为不是在讲课中翻转，
so if an arrow points from A to B then A depends on B.
因此，如果箭头从A指向B，则A取决于B。
And we're looking at the other way around.
我们正在寻找另一种方式。
In lecture, based on the graph you
在讲座中，基于图形
gave, if the arrow goes from A to B, then A depends on B.
如果箭头从A到B，则A取决于B。
PROFESSOR: If the arrow goes from A to B, then what?
教授：如果箭头从A到B，那又如何？
AUDIENCE: If you're saying A is a prerequisite for B and G,
听众：如果您说A是B和G的前提，
then we just sweep from left to right and say,
然后我们从左到右扫一下，然后说
I have to do this.
我必须这样做
And then those two.
然后是那两个。
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
They have to--
他们必须 -
AUDIENCE: It's the order that-- because when you're doing DFS,
听众：这是顺序，因为在执行DFS时，
you recurse.
你递归。
It's the order that they finished the recurse.
他们完成递归的顺序是这样。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
You have the right answer.
您有正确的答案。
I'm just trying to build out the annotation for it.
我只是想为其建立注释。
I'm pretty sure this is the right way.
我很确定这是正确的方法。
I can look at this, but I can't promise you
我可以看一下，但是我不能答应你
that this is the right way because I coded it
这是正确的方法，因为我编码了
and it works.
而且有效。
So no.
所以不行。
This is the right way.
这是正确的方法。
Yes.
是。
This is the right way to represent them.
这是代表它们的正确方法。
So forward edge means B depends on A.
因此，前缘意味着B取决于A。
OK.
好。
So let's figure out how we do this.
因此，让我们弄清楚我们如何做到这一点。
Let's do this in pseudo-code and then build
让我们用伪代码执行此操作，然后构建
the intuition for it.
直觉。
So you said reverse of the finishing times.
所以您说了整理时间的倒转。
So let's build a list that has all the nodes
因此，让我们建立一个包含所有节点的列表
in the order of their finishing times.
按照完成时间的顺序。
So let's build a list finished that is empty at first.
因此，让我们建立一个最初为空的完成列表。
Then I'm going to add all the nodes in the list
然后，我将添加列表中的所有节点
as I'm done with them.
因为我已经处理完了。
And then I'll reverse the list.
然后，我将反转列表。
Where do I add nodes to the list?
如何在列表中添加节点？
AUDIENCE: In the check.
听众：在支票上。
Line 2.75.
行2.75。
PROFESSOR: Not quite.
教授：不完全是。
So line 4.
所以第4行
So I'm adding them in the order in which I'm done with them.
因此，我将按照完成它们的顺序添加它们。
So when I'm about to leave a node completely,
所以当我要完全离开一个节点时，
I'll add it to that list.
我将其添加到该列表中。
Which node?
哪个节点？
What's the name?
什么名字？
AUDIENCE: V.
听众：V.
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
And then where can I reverse the list?
然后在哪里可以倒转清单？
AUDIENCE: Line 4 of the first--
听众：第一行的第4行-
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
How would I do this?
我该怎么做？
r dot finished dot reverse.
r点完成点反转。
Like this?
像这样？
AUDIENCE: I think that's OK in Python.
听众：我认为Python是可以的。
PROFESSOR: I think so, too.
教授：我也这样认为。
So this will give me a topological sort.
因此，这将给我一种拓扑结构。
Let's figure out why this works intuitively.
让我们弄清楚为什么它直观地起作用。
Yes?
是？
So while we're building the topological sort,
因此，当我们构建拓扑排序时，
while we're building the inverse of the final list.
而我们正在建立最终列表的反面。
So the first thing that we put in the list
所以我们放在清单中的第一件事
is the last class we're going to take.
是我们要参加的最后一堂课。
So as I go forward in this graph,
所以当我在这张图中前进时，
my VFS is going to go A, B, C, D, E. There's nothing after E.
我的VFS将转到A，B，C，D，E。E之后什么也没有。
And it's done with E.
这是用E完成的。
So this means there is no class that depends on E. Otherwise,
因此，这意味着不存在依赖于E的类。否则，
DFS would keep recursing.
DFS将继续递归。
So E is the last class I take.
因此，E是我参加的最后一堂课。
If I take this last, there's definitely no dependencies
如果我坚持下去，肯定没有依赖关系
that I'm violating.
我违反了。
All right?
好吧？
So it's safe to start with E.
因此从E开始很安全。
Now I'm out of E, I'm back to D. I go from D to F, I print that.
现在我不在E中，回到D。我从D转到F，然后打印出来。
Let's not worry about this for a little bit.
让我们不必为此担心。
And let's go back to D. When DFS comes
让我们回到D。
back, it's going to print D. So I
返回，它将打印D。所以我
know that by the time DFS is out,
知道在DFS出现时，
I printed all the classes that depend on D. Right?
我打印了所有依赖于D的类。对吗？
So when I'm at D, whenever I have forward
所以当我在D时，只要我向前
edges that I haven't visited yet,
我还没去过的地方
I will call DFS visit on them.
我将致电DFS访问他们。
DFS visit returns before I can get out of D.
在我离开D之前，DFS访问将返回。
So all the edges that depend on D have been printed.
因此，所有依赖于D的边缘均已打印。
Sorry.
抱歉。
All the nodes that depend on D have been printed.
依赖于D的所有节点均已打印。
So when I get out of D, I know that all the nodes that
所以当我离开D时，我知道所有的节点
depend on D have been printed, so it's
取决于D已被打印，所以
safe to print D. This is the intuition
可以安全地打印D。这是直觉
behind topological sort.
后面的拓扑排序。
So you can build sort of an induction proof based on this.
因此，您可以基于此构建归纳证明。
So whenever I'm here, I assume that all the nodes
因此，只要我在这里，我就假设所有节点
that I have forward edges to are somewhere in my results.
在结果中我有前锋。
So I can include my nodes.
因此，我可以包含我的节点。
So this means that whenever you put a node here,
因此，这意味着每当您在此处放置节点时，
all the nodes that have forward edges to this node
具有该节点的前向边缘的所有节点
have already been output.
已经输出。
So this means that no dependency relationships
所以这意味着没有依赖关系
are going to be violated.
将会受到侵犯。
OK.
好。
Let's keep building this and see the result.
让我们继续构建它并查看结果。
So D, E, F, we get out of B. We get out
所以D，E，F从B中脱身。
of C. What do we do here?
C.我们在这里做什么？
Print C, right?
打印C，对不对？
What classes depend on C?
哪些类取决于C？
D, E, and F. I had a tree edge to D.
D，E和F。我对D有树的边缘。
I had DFS visit here, so I know that all the classes that
我在这里访问了DFS，所以我知道
depend on C because they depend on D have been output.
依赖于C，因为它们依赖于D已被输出。
And then I have a forward edge on F.
然后我在F上有优势。
So I didn't recurse from C to F, but I
所以我没有从C递归到F，但是我
know that has been covered somewhere.
知道已经被某个地方覆盖了。
Right?
对？
Forward edge means that I've already seen it in DFS,
前缘意味着我已经在DFS中看到了它，
and that I've already returned from it.
而且我已经从中回来了。
So it has already been printed.
因此它已经被打印了。
So I'm going to write this.
所以我要写这个。
Now I get out of C. I get out of B. I go into G. I get out of B,
现在我离开C。我离开B。我进入G。我离开B，
and I go into A. And I go out of A, and I print it.
然后进入A。然后离开A，然后打印出来。
OK.
好。
So I have tree edges that I can handle.
所以我有可以处理的树边缘。
So these are all tree edges.
这些都是树的边缘。
And the reason that topological sorting works on tree edges
以及在树边缘进行拓扑排序的原因
is that I call DFS visit on the tree edge,
是我在树边缘调用DFS访问，
and I know it returns by the time I return.
我知道当我回来的时候它会回来。
So I know that whatever's underneath
所以我知道下面有什么
that tree has already been printed.
那棵树已经被打印了。
I have forward edges that will just take me forward
我有前进的优势，只会带我前进
in the DFS.
在DFS中。
So I know that by the time I return from a node,
所以我知道当我从节点返回时，
I've already returned from all the nodes
我已经从所有节点回来了
that I have forward edges to because they're
我有前进的优势，因为他们
lower in the tree.
在树下。
Right?
对？
Forward edges work like this.
前边缘的工作原理是这样的。
So by the time I'm out of C, I've
所以当我没C的时候，我已经
definitely printed F. Now I have this cross edge from G to C.
绝对是F。现在我有了从G到C的交叉边缘。
A cross edge means that there is no direct relationship here,
交叉边缘表示此处没有直接关系，
but I've already visited C. If there's no direct relationship,
但我已经去过C。如果没有直接关系，
it means that for sure I'm done visiting C
这意味着我肯定已经完成了C的访问
and I've returned so that I can get to G.
我回来了，这样我就可以去G了。
So there's some common parent between C and G.
因此，C和G之间有一些共同的父母。
I'm already done with C, and I've returned to that parent.
我已经用完C了，已经回到了那个父母那里。
And then I went to G.
然后我去了G。
So all the nodes that are pointed to my cross edges
所以所有指向我交叉边缘的节点
have also been printed in topological sort.
也以拓扑形式打印。
OK.
好。
Now what about back edges?
现在后边缘呢？
What if I had a back edge?
如果我有后缘怎么办？
What if I had this back edge between C and A?
如果我的后缘介于C和A之间怎么办？
What happens then?
那会发生什么呢？
If I had a back edge, then that would break topological sort.
如果我有后缘，那将破坏拓扑结构。
Right?
对？
Because this is saying that hey, you
因为这是说嘿，你
should print A before you print C.
在打印C之前应打印A。
But I know that I'm going to come out of C way
但是我知道我会从C语言中脱颖而出
before I have a chance to come out of A.
在我有机会从A出来之前
So if I have a back edge, topological sort doesn't work.
因此，如果我有后端，则无法进行拓扑排序。
When do I have a back edge?
什么时候有后缘？
When I have a cycle.
当我有一个周期。
So this is why I don't care about back edges.
因此，这就是为什么我不在乎后边缘的原因。
Back edges [INAUDIBLE] cycles.
后边缘[音频不清晰]循环。
So back edge means I have a path forward.
所以后缘意味着我有前进的道路。
And I have a path backward.
我有一条向后的路。
That does a cycle.
那做一个循环。
OK.
好。
There's an awful lot of silence here.
这里有很多沉默。
Does everything makes sense or?
一切都有意义吗？
OK.
好。
Any questions?
任何问题？
Nope?
不？
Everyone's happy?
大家开心吗
So you don't need to reason about this formally.
因此，您无需正式地对此进行推理。
Just remember the intuition that the reason we're printing them
只要记住直觉，我们打印它们的原因
in this order is the first thing you
按此顺序是您的第一件事
print is the last class you're going to take.
打印是您要参加的最后一堂课。
Because for sure there are no dependencies left on it,
因为可以肯定的是，这里没有任何依赖关系，
otherwise DFS would keep recursing.
否则，DFS将继续递归。
And then there's that recursive structure that makes this work.
然后有一个递归结构使这项工作有效。
OK.
好。
Cool.
凉。